radissonsas.com 2014-08-19

# THE REZIDOR HOTEL GROUP - Privacy & Cookie policy

## 2012 Privacy Policy

### What this Policy Covers

This guest privacy policy ("Policy") describes how we at the Rezidor Hotel Group, acting through our Danish entity Rezidor Hotels ApS Danmark in respect of our websites, or any other affiliate ("Rezidor") collect, use, share, and protect our guests' personal information. "Personal information" is information, recorded in any format that identifies you personally, by itself or together with other information that is available to us. The use of applied web technology is described in our “Cookie Policy”.

This Policy does not apply to the practices of businesses or websites which we do not own or control, not to people we do not employ or manage. The Rezidor Hotel Group operates itself and licenses others to operate hotels in Europe, the Middle East and Africa under the brands "Radisson Blu", "Park Inn" and "Country Inns & Suites", "Quorvus Collection" and "Radisson Red".

Some of the Rezidor Brand Hotels are owned and operated by independent franchisees. **This Policy does not cover our franchisees' privacy practices**. When you provide personal information directly to one of our franchisees, the franchisee's privacy policy will apply. Please note that we require our franchisees to have privacy policies that are consistent with our Privacy Commitment and to comply with all applicable privacy and data protection laws, though their actual privacy policies may be different from this Policy.

Our sites may include links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Rezidor. In some cases, when linking to another site you may still see our branding even though you are actually reviewing content provided by a third party. If you submit personal information while on those sites, your information is subject to their privacy policies and you should review those policies.

### Your Consent to This Policy

This Policy is part of the terms and conditions that govern your use of our services. By using our websites, the central reservation system, staying at any of the Rezidor Brand Hotels, you are agreeing for us to use your personal information in accordance with the applicable laws. We will keep your personal information as long as we need it for the purposes of which we collected it, or as permitted by law.

### Personal information we collect about you

  * We collect transactional information (such as your name, email address, telephone number, reservation data) as well as information you actively provide to us, for example, when you book a reservation through our central reservation service, stay at any Rezidor Brand Hotel, subscribe to any of our newsletters.
  * We collect personal information about our guests from public sources and from other companies that have the right to share that information with us.
  * If you provide us personal information about others, for example, in a "Send to a Friend" feature, or if others give us your information, we will only use that information for the specific reason for which it was provided to us. We do not store this information.

### We do not knowingly collect personal information from children

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If you believe your child has provided personal information to us, please contact us so that we can identify and delete your child's personal information.

### Purpose for collection of your personal information

We use your personal information:

  * to provide the services you request;
  * to personalize your experience when you stay at a Rezidor Brand Hotel
  * to support the functionality and to personalize the layout and content of our websites to match your needs, interests and preferences
  * subject to your consent to send you promotional messages and special offers based on your privacy preferences;
  * for security and fraud prevention purposes;
  * to better understand our guests;
  * to improve our programs, services and websites; and
  * to better market our programs and services.

### Use of your personal information for marketing purposes

You may choose whether you wish to receive marketing communications from us, and you may change your privacy preferences at any time by giving us written notice at the address communicated to you when subscribing and receiving marketing information or at the Rezidor Hotel Group's Data Protection Office.

If you choose not to receive any promotional communications from us, we will not send you purely promotional messages and will not share your personal information with other companies. We may still contact you for customer research or administrative purposes, such as confirming a reservation or transaction you've made.

### Sharing of your personal information with others

We may share your personal information in the following ways:

  * We share your personal information among the companies of the Rezidor Hotel Group to the extent necessary to ensure that your requested services are delivered to you in a satisfactory way; for that same purpose, we also share your personal information with Carlson Companies Inc., or any of its affiliates, if such is necessary to complete our services to you (for example, reservation, cancellation, booking changes, loyalty program membership, etc.).
  * We share your personal information with companies that perform services on our behalf, such as companies providing application management and technical infrastructure support.
  * Based upon your privacy preferences, we may share your personal information with other companies within the Rezidor Hotel Group, other companies selected by Rezidor, including strategic partners who will use it to send you promotions and special offers they believe will be of interest to you.

Our service providers, strategic partners, and Rezidor Brand Hotels are bound by contract to use the personal information we share with them only for the limited purposes for which we provide it to them and to take appropriate measures to protect the confidentiality, integrity and security of your personal information. They may not use or share your personal information in a manner that would be inconsistent with our promises to you, and they must comply with all applicable privacy and data protection laws.

We may transfer your personal information to another entity that has acquired the stock or substantially all of the assets of Rezidor, for example, as the result of a sale, merger, or reorganization, insolvency, dissolution or liquidation, provided that the acquiring entity's use of your personal information will still be subject to this Policy.

We may share or transfer your personal information to unrelated third parties, if disclosure is required to comply with a law, regulatory requirement, court order, or a subpoena; to cooperate with law enforcement or other governmental investigations; to protect your and our legal rights, property and safety, our employees, agents, other guests.

### Protection of your personal information

We implement appropriate physical, technical and organizational security for the management and transmission of personal data, including appropriate security measures to protect such data from accidental or unlawful destruction or accidental loss, misuse, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access and all other unlawful forms of processing.

### Cross Border Transfer of your personal information

Our websites and databases currently reside on servers in Denmark and the USA; we co-operate with sub-contracted data processors in various countries. We request data processors to strictly adhere to the data protection legislation pursuant to the EU Directive 95/46/EC; and we instruct our partners accordingly; several data are sent on to the Carlson Companies Inc.'s server in the United States in order to effect reservations, cancellations, booking amendments in the central reservation system located in Omaha, Nebraska, USA. Different countries have different data protection laws, some of which provide more protection than others. If and when we transfer your personal information from one country to another country, we take appropriate measures to protect your privacy and personal information in accordance with the EU legislation for international data transfers (including the requirement of certification under the Safe Harbor Framework). By using our websites, participating in our programs, or staying at Rezidor Brand Hotels, you are consenting to the transfer of your personal information to any country in the world in accordance with the terms of this Policy.

### Cookies and Other Web Technologies

When you visit one of our websites, we may use the following web technologies to track your navigation on the website and aggregate further non-personal information as described in our [Cookie Policy](http://www.radissonblu/privacy-policy/cookies). Where your consent to the use of cookies is required, we will not set cookies without your prior consent.

### Transparency

To review the information we have about you, contact us at Rezidor's Data Protection Office (as set out below) and request that a copy of your personal profile be delivered to your home or e-mail address. We will use secure means to confirm your identity to prevent the wrong people from accessing your information. If you have corrections, we will respond to your request within a reasonable delay. To remove your information from our files, contact us to request that all information pertaining to you be deleted.

 **The Rezidor Hotel Group's Data Protection Office**  
Avenue du Bourget 44  
1130 Brussels  
Belgium  
Tel : +32 2 702 9200  
Fax: +32 2 702 9300  
Email: [privacy@rezidor.com](mailto:privacy@rezidor.com)

The Rezidor Hotel Group’s privacy policy applies to the Radisson Blu, Park Inn by Radisson, Quorvus Collection and Radisson Red hotels located in Europe, the Middle East and Africa, while hotels in the US and Canada come under the privacy policy of Carlson Hotels Worldwide.

### [Privacy Policy Promises - Rezidor](http://www.radissonblu.com/privacy-policy/rezidor/promises/)

Within the Rezidor Hotel Group we take data privacy protection seriously. Here are our ten promises to you as our hotel guest or visitor of our websites:

  1.  **Notice.** When we collect your personal information, we will give you timely and appropriate notice describing what personal information we are collecting, how we will use it, and the types of third parties with whom we may share it.
  2.  **Choice.** When subscribing to any of our newsletters or participating in our marketing events we will give you choices about the ways we use and share your personal information and we will respect the choices you make.
  3.  **Relevance.** We will collect only as much personal information as we need for specific, identified purposes, and we will not use it for other purposes without obtaining your consent.
  4.  **Retention.** We will keep your personal information only as long as we need it for the purposes for which we collected it, or as permitted by law.
  5.  **Accuracy.** We strive to ensure the personal information in our records is accurate.
  6.  **Access.** Upon your request we will inform you about your personal information stored in our data bases as required by law.
  7.  **Security.** We will take appropriate physical, technical, and administrative measures to protect your personal information from loss and unauthorized use, access, disclosure, alteration or destruction.
  8.  **Sharing.** Except as described in this Policy, we will not share your personal information with third parties without your consent.
  9.  **International Transfer.** If we transfer your personal information to a country outside the territory governed by the EU legislation (including Switzerland, Norway and Iceland), we will take appropriate measures to protect your privacy and the personal information we transfer in accordance with the applicable law.
  10.  **Enforcement.** We will regularly review how we are meeting these privacy promises.

To access your information, ask questions about our privacy practices, change your marketing preferences or issue a complaint, contact us at:

 **The Rezidor Hotel Group's Data Protection Office**  
Avenue du Bourget 44  
1130 Brussels  
Belgium  
Tel: +32 2 702 9200  
Fax: +32 2 702 9300  
Email: [privacy@rezidor.com](mailto:privacy@rezidor.com)

### [Privacy Policy Promises – Carlson](http://www.radissonblu.com/privacy-policy/carlson/promises/)

Carlson Hotels Worldwide Guest Privacy Policy – Effective Carlson Hotels Guest Privacy Policy – Effective October 28, 2007.  
Last Updated - March 31, 2011

 **Carlson Hotels Privacy Promises.**  
Carlson Hotels together with its subsidiaries (collectively, "Carlson Hotels") take your privacy seriously. These are our ten promises to you:

  *  **Notice.** When we collect your personal information, we will give you timely and appropriate notice describing what personal information we are collecting, how we will use it, and the types of third parties with whom we may share it.
  *  **Choice.** We will give you choices about the ways we use and share your personal information, and we will respect the choices you make.
  *  **Relevance.** We will collect only as much personal information as we need for specific, identified purposes, and we will not use it for other purposes without obtaining your consent.
  *  **Retention.** We will keep your personal information only as long as we need it for the purposes for which we collected it, or as permitted by law.
  *  **Accuracy.** We will take appropriate steps to make sure the personal information in our records is accurate.
  *  **Access.** We will provide ways for you to access your personal information as required by law, so you can correct inaccuracies.
  *  **Security.** We will take appropriate physical, technical, and administrative measures to protect your personal information from loss and unauthorized use, access, disclosure, alteration or destruction.
  *  **Sharing.** Except as described in this Policy, we will not share your personal information with third parties without your consent.
  *  **International Transfer.** If we transfer your personal information to another country, we will take appropriate measures to protect your privacy and the personal information we transfer in accordance with the applicable law.
  *  **Enforcement.** We will regularly review how we are meeting these privacy promises, and we will provide an independent way to resolve complaints about our privacy practices.

To access your information, ask questions about our privacy practices, change your marketing preferences or issue a complaint, contact us at:

 **Carlson Hotels**  
Customer Service  
11340 Blondo St.  
Omaha, NE 68164

In the U.S. & Canada call toll free at +1 (888) 201-1719.  
Email: privacy@radisson.com.

If your inquiry is not satisfactorily addressed, contact the TRUSTe Dispute Resolution Process at <http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint>. TRUSTe will serve as a liaison with the website to resolve your concerns.

## 2012 Cookie Policy

This web technology policy ("Cookie Policy") describes how we at the Rezidor Hotel Group, acting through our Danish entity Rezidor Hotels ApS Danmark, operate our websites while safeguarding the website visitors’ interests in data privacy.

### Web Technology Used

When you visit one of our websites, we may use the following web technologies:

 **Cookies:** Subject to your web browser’s settings, we collect information that is sent to us automatically by your web browser when you access our websites by help of a cookie. This information typically includes the IP address currently assigned to your computer and the type of operating system and browser installed.

A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your computer's hard disk by a web server.

We distinguish between "session cookies" and "persistent cookies".

## Change Cookie Preferences

 **Session Cookies:** We use session cookies to assign a randomly-generated unique identification number to your computer each time you visit one of our websites. A session cookie expires after you close your browser. We use session cookies to support the functionality of our websites and to understand your use of our websites, i.e. which pages you visit, which links you use, and how long you stay on each page.

 **Persistent cookies:** Where admitted, we use persistent cookies, which do not expire immediately after you close your browser, but stay on your computer until they expire after a set period of time or you delete them. Each time you visit any of our websites, our web server will recognize the persistent cookie on your computer's hard drive. By assigning your computer a persistent, unique identifier, we are able to create a database of your previous choices and preferences. The unique identifier also helps us to keep a more accurate account of how often you visit our websites, how often you return, how your use of our websites may vary over time, and the effectiveness of our promotional efforts. This information is however not revealing your personal data, it solely reveals movements made on your computer. If you access our websites through an e-mail we have sent you or you've created a "user identity" during one of your visits, the information provided by our or our third party service provider’s cookies may be linked to information in our records that identifies you personally.

 **Consent to Use Cookies:** Session cookies do not require your prior consent, if they are necessary for the functioning of the website and will expire once you have left the site. Persistent cookies that track your previous choices and preferences but are not necessary for the functioning of the website require your express prior consent. We will not send you any third-party persistent cookie until you have consented through an opt-in function on our websites. When you do consent, we will set a persistent cookie that will track your cookie preference for future site visits. For a list of cookies on our websites and their purpose, click here. Please keep in mind that while these cookies may not be necessary, they are mainly used to customize and thereby improve your website experience.

 **Web Beacons:** The pages on our websites may contain electronic images known as "web beacons" - sometimes called "single-pixel gifs" or "clear gifs." We use these web beacons to learn more about the ways visitors use our web sites and to measure the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns. We may also include web beacons in promotional e-mail messages in order to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon. elink information obtained using any web beacons to other information that identifies you personally.

 **Cookies currently used on the websites**  
The current state of our cookie use, their purpose, intrusiveness and persistence is as follows:

  * Consent Cookie
  * Session ID
  * Analytics
  * Site Navigation 
  * 3rd party Cookies
  * Flash Local Shared (LSO)
  * Other

 **Consent Cookie:** Once a user chooses to consent to our use of cookies, as outlined on this page, then we may place a cookie on your computer. This only stores the word "true" or the word “false” and is not set to expire in the near future, after consent is given.

 **Session IDs:** Our web server may create session cookies which are essential for your use of some of the interactive elements of the website, such as contact forms and logging in. The cookie contains a session ID which is a mechanism for distinguishing your visit to our website from any other visitors that may be using the website at the same time. Session cookies are considered necessary for the use of the website and do not require your consent.

 **Analytics:** We use Google Analytics, which creates a number of first-party cookies, which allow us to ensure that subsequent visits to our website are recorded as belonging to the same (unique) visitor and to show us how you found us.

 **Content Management and Site Navigation:** Our content management tool creates a number of first-party cookies, which are session cookies and are deleted when you close your browser. These cookies help our websites to function correctly. This data is aggregated and not personally identifiable.

We use the data that is collected using these first-party cookies to report, in aggregate, how our visitors find and use our website; we use those reports to understand overall visitor behaviour and we use that understanding to update and improve our websites.

 **Third-party Cookies**  
Third party cookies are cookies created by our partners; when allowing these partners to embed a cookie on a page of any of our websites, we request them to obtain your prior consent before collecting information through such cookie. As well as using cookies from our advertising partners, from time to time we may also embed external content from other third party websites within our website. These cookies are specific to the third party’s domain and accordingly the data held in them can be seen and managed by the third party solely. These include sites such as Facebook and Twitter, whose cookie usage policy you can view on their own websites. We also use the Google Maps tools on the basis that Google adheres to its privacy policy, we use the “like” plug-in of Facebook on the basis that Facebook adheres to its data use policy. The use of these plugins represents current best practice. We have ni direct control over the content of the cookies these plugins create.

 **Flash Local Shared Object (LSO) storage**  
We may periodically use the YouTube service to host video content and embed YouTube's player in our web pages to allow you to watch the video without leaving our website. YouTube's embedded player currently creates and updates a Flash LSO. We have no direct control over YouTube's use of the data stored in this object. For more information, please refer to YouTube’s privacy policy.

 **Other cookies we may be using**  
We occasionally trial other services which may create cookies on your computer. If we are currently doing so then these trials will be listed here.
